Erik Hoffman

Address: 68 Abell St. Toronto, Ontario, M6J0B1|Home Phone#: 1-289-383-4992|Email: erik_hoffman@outlook.com Website: erikhoffmancs.com

WORK OBJECTIVE

To find a position that allows me to use my strong background in computer science and software engineering skills to work on innovative technologies and modern applications. In combination with these core credentials I would apply my well developed team working abilities gleaned from both my work and school experience in software development life cycles. I believe that a foundation in critical thinking and perfect communication with your team go hand-in-hand in creating successful projects.

QUALIFICATIONS

- → Multiple years of programming in C, Python, Java, HTML, Javascript, AngularJS, NodeJS, C++, CSS
- → Working knowledge and experience for revision softwares like git/svn in command line and IDE use
- → Knowledge of command line interface and working in Linux environments
- → Experience and course knowledge on database management and creation
- → Strong mathematics background from minor in mathematics

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF GUELPH

Guelph, ON

Bachelor of Computing Honours (B.Comp)

Fall 2012 - Fall 2016

Computer Science Major, Mathematics Minor

Notable Courses Completed: Data Structures, Networking and Web Development, Operating Systems, Discrete Mathematics, Combinatorics and Graph Theory, Algorithms, Security (RSA and prime mathematics), Microprocessors and Assembly Language, Theory of Computation, Databases, Artificial Intelligence, File Storage Structures and Data Retrieval.

BRADFORD DISTRICT HIGH SCHOOL

Bradford, ON

Fall 2007 - June 2011

Took Computer Science courses starting in grade 10, Ontario Scholar all 4 years

WORK EXPERIENCE

CANADIAN IMPERIAL BANK OF COMMERCE (CIBC)

Toronto, ON

Intermediate Applications Developer

January 2017 - Present

- → Placed onto a multi-million dollar budget project in order to develop full stack solutions for business requirements, working with multiple teams around the world
- → Architect systems and APIs to meet business needs
- → Used current technologies such as Angular2, NodeJS, KarmaJS, Jira, Bitbucket, Jenkins
- → Performed code reviews on many developers pull requests, no code deployed without a review
- → Integrated older applications into the new one, following rigid design uniforms across the platforms

UNIVERSITY OF GUELPH

Guelph, ON

Teaching Assistant for Introduction to Computing

September 2016 - Fall 2016

- → Assist students with learning basics of an array of applications: Word, Excel, Powerpoint and Access as well as teaching some Javascript
- → Conducted office hours, answered emails and graded assignments